

TOLULOPE OGUNLEYE

MOBILE ENGINEER

PROFILE

Adaptable Software Engineer with over 9 years overall software development experience, 6+ years of experience designing and building cutting-edge Android apps for mobile devices in the e-commerce, and financial industries. Built a payment app with 10K+ downloads.

EXPERIENCE

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mobinet Solutions - Lagos, Nigeria

Oct 2021 - Present

- Led developers in designing and developing banking app that has processed over NGN2billion in less than a year.
- Architect Android applications with MVP pattern and dependency injection using Dagger2.
- Implemented features for various android applications using Java or Kotlin and built cross-platform apps using Flutter.
- Implemented CI/CD for android apps which made them get to market 20% faster.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (MOBILE DEVELOPER) Mobinet Solutions - Lagos, Nigeria Sept 2018 - Oct 2021

- Collaborated with engineers, user research, product management, design, and support teams to ensure quality in all phases of app development.
- Implemented Clean Architecture using Dagger2 and RxJava.
- Defined and implemented robust app architectures and complex user interfaces.
- Developed payment app that leverage on QR technology which help avoid contact during payment with Flutter using Cubit.
- Conceptualize, develop, and test native Android applications, including UI, core functionality, and third-party SDKS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (ANDROID DEVELOPER)

Satconcepts ICT Ltd - Lagos, Nigeria

Sept 2015 - Aug 2018

- Collaborated with designers, engineers, and product managers to build android apps with engaging UIs.
- Refactored a major part of an e-book reader Android app, improving app performance from 92% crash-free sessions to 99.9%.
- Hands on experience in integrating REST APIs using Retrofit2

+2347036443808

tjcode19@gmail.com

Lagos, Nigeria

https://github.com/tjcode19

(in) linkedln.com/in/tjcode19

EDUCATION

BSC. (ED) IN PHYSICS
Obafemi Awolowo University

2007 - 2010

SKILLS

- · Software engineering
- Design patterns
- Analytical skill
- Android development/architecture
- Creative problem solving
- Teamwork and communication